radioplayer.co.uk 2017-12-03

# Privacy Policy | Radioplayer

The privacy of our users is important to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information received and collected by Radioplayer and how it is used.

### Log files

Like many other Web sites, [www.radioplayer.co.uk](http://www.radioplayer.co.uk/) makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks. We use this information to analyse trends, administer the site, track user’s movements around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

### Cookies

The Radioplayer website at [www.radioplayer.co.uk](http://www.radioplayer.co.uk/) does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser. Again, none of this is personally identifiable.

### Blog posts

If you contribute to our blog, we will collect potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users. We only disclose logged- in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that we use and disclose personally-identifying information as described above, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

### Location services

Radioplayer uses your approximate location to provide an enhanced experience, ensuring we offer stations that are geographically relevant to the locality you’re currently in. Our smartphone and tablet apps use your location for this and for providing better, more relevant station and on-demand recommendations. To turn off this functionality, look for an option in the Settings menu or switch off location services on your phone (or block Radioplayer). Radioplayer products continue to work, even if no location data is available.

## The Radioplayer web-based listening console

### Common console features

Radioplayer also uses cookies* and collects search terms and IP addresses (an IP address is a number that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet) from visitors. You can read more about how we use cookies in the Radioplayer web-based console here. The reason we use cookies is to...

  * Allow users to personalise their Radioplayer experience – for example by setting stations as favourites in the My Stations feature.
  * Analyse and improve the service we offer – for example by understanding how often visitors return to a Radioplayer station, or what they search for most.
  * Track the growth of Radioplayer and market it as a service. We may disclose information in aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) for marketing purposes.
  * Radioplayer will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies).

Sometimes Radioplayer will use third parties to process your information. If we do so, we will require that they don’t use your personal information for their own business purposes, unless you have explicitly consented to the use of your personal information in this way.

### Google Analytics

Radioplayer uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics sets a cookie* in order to evaluate your use of Radioplayer and compile reports for us on activity across the Radioplayer network.

Radioplayer uses Google Analytics with the “anonymizeIP()” function, which ensures that your IP address is shortened before it is stored and therefore cannot be linked directly to you.  
Google stores the information collected by the cookie* on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your anonymised IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

For more information on the cookie* set by Google Analytics, including information on how to opt out please view [Google's privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacypolicy.html).

### Third party sites beyond Radioplayer

Both the Radioplayer website and the Radioplayer listening console contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties (for example radio stations which have chosen to join Radioplayer).

These third party websites have their own privacy policies, including cookies*, and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit or data which is collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

### Radioplayer Social Apps

By using our Social Apps, you agree that your personal information will be handled as described in this Policy.

### Technical Information

We typically use the information gathered in anonymous or aggregate form to analyse ways to improve our Social Apps. In some cases, we may convert the user ID that your social networking site provides to us into a unique, anonymous identifier. By using the non-personally identifiable information that is associated with the unique, anonymous identifier, we can personalise your experience, recommend media based on your preferences and use of the Social Apps without personally identifying you.

### Information We Collect Through Social Networking

When you use one of our Social Apps or when you connect to a social networking site through one of our services, we may record information regarding your use of that App. We also may collect other information that is visible on your social networking profile or site when your social networking service provider permits us to do so, or when you choose to allow your social networking service provider to provide the information to Radioplayer. This information may include, but is not limited to, your name, profile picture, gender, user ID, email address, your country, your language, your time zone, the organisations and links on your profile page, the names and profile pictures of your social networking site “friends” and other information you have included in your social networking site profile.

You may choose not to allow your social networking site to provide us with certain information about you, but then you might not be able to use the Social Apps or take advantage of all of the features.

### How We Use Your Information

We may use the information we collect about you for any of the following purposes...

  * To improve our Social Apps by providing personalised experiences and recommendations, language and location customisation, personalised help and instructions, or other responses to your usage of Radioplayer.
  * To better understand how users access and use Radioplayer, our Social Apps, on an aggregated and individualised basis, for the purposes of improving our products and services, and to respond to customer desires and preferences.
  * To provide you with Radioplayer news and newsletters.

### How and When We Share Information

Information about our users is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling or renting it to others. We may employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include sending postal mail and e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, analysing data, and providing marketing assistance. These third parties have access to the personal information needed to perform their functions on our behalf. We require these companies to agree (1) to provide adequate protections for your personal information that are no less protective than those set out in this Policy and (2) to use your personal information only for the purposes for which the third party has been engaged by us.

### Questions and comments

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to get in touch.

*A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier, sent to your computer or device from a website and stored on your device’s hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you. Users can set their devices to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The latter means that certain personalised features cannot then be provided to that user and accordingly they may not be able to take full advantage of all of the website’s features.
